# **Kevin Lamping**

210-896-3868 <u>me@klamp.in</u> <u>kevinlamping.com</u> San Antonio, Tx

Senior Front-end Engineer with experience in a variety of areas including: automated testing (both unit and functional), web applications (e.g. Angular/React), build systems, accessibility, responsive design, and back-end integration.

## **Popular Projects**

#### LEARN.WEBDRIVER.IO

Online video course teaching essentials of WebdriverlO test framework, featuring 50+ "bite-sized" videos detailing the various aspects of the tool.

#### VISUALREGRESSIONTESTING.COM

Collection of links to articles, videos and tools related to visual regression testing. Includes a free 5-day email course on teaching WebdriverCSS usage.

# Professional Experience

FRONT-END TESTER (CONTRACTOR), RESERVE.COM; REMOTE – OCT 2017 - May 2018 Responsibilities include:

- Development of new functional test framework using WebdriverlO, Sauce Labs, Appium and Applitools.
- Creation of new set of functional tests for iOS app and web presence.
- Integration of test framework with build system, including CircleCl and Allure reporter.
- Creation of new WebdriverIO services to extend that capabilities of the tool, primarily wdio-applitools-service and wdio-responsive-service

### FRONT-END ENGINEER (CONTRACTOR), USAA; REMOTE - OCT 2016 - JAN 2018

Member of the presentation infrastructure team. Responsibilities include:

- Development of new React components for use in company-wide component library
- Maintenance of existing components, including bug fixes and new features
- Strict adherence to code quality guidelines, including test coverage and accessibility requirements

## SENIOR FRONT-END ENGINEER, INVISIONAPP; REMOTE – JUNE 2015- AUG 2016

Member of the front-end infrastructure team. Responsibilities include:

- Creation of a functional test framework using WebdriverIO, allowing developers and QA leads the ability to write and run test automation both locally and through Jenkins.
- Migration of API service functionality to NodeJS microservices

#### FRONT-END ENGINEER, FOUR KITCHENS; REMOTE – JAN 2015 - JUNE 2015

Worked on team of seven to develop a Headless Drupal website for twit.tv, consisting of a Node.js front-end and Drupal RESTful API.

- Node work, including setting up an Express server that uses Dust.js for page templating.
- Client-side development of a fully responsive website that works on all major modern browsers and devices.

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER, RACKSPACE; SAN ANTONIO, TX - AUG 2013 - JAN 2015

Front-end Engineer with a focus on JavaScript, specifically developing a large-scale internal AngularJS application.

- Creation of new Angular components for Encore-UI framework.
- Define a set of coding style guidelines and standards for JavaScript, CSS and HTML.
- Encouraged adherence to guidelines via JSHint, JSCS, CSS Lint and Istanbul.
- Built out a CICD process using TravisCl, which was focused on catching regression errors through unit and functional tests.
- Mentored teammates new to TDD. Helped them understand the concepts behind it and how to implement them in JavaScript.

### SENIOR FRONT-END ENGINEER, USAA; SAN ANTONIO, TX – SEP 2009 - JULY 2013

Primary Front-end Engineer responsible for infrastructure HTML, CSS, JS driving usaa.com, a site with over 2000 pages of content. Worked on an enterprise-level team providing support, training and functionality to an IT department with over 3000 individuals.

- Provided support in on-call situations, including debugging applications with production defects.
- Created a new page on-the-fly in less than 3 hours as a stop-gap solution, providing time for teams to triage a major production outage.
- Worked within a 10+ person team to introduce a brand-new component based infrastructure, enabling faster development for product teams across USAA.
- Mentored several new hires on ins-and-outs of USAA. Provided them with opportunities
  to work on real production defects while giving guidance and feedback on the solution
  they chose.

## Education

B.A. in Arts and Technology - The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, Texas